Guide to the Howard Zinn Papers TAM.542
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VIII: Subject Files, 1933-2010
  - Violence/Nonviolence: John Brown's Raid, 1970, undated; cuid17020 (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Violence/Nonviolence: Notes, undated; cuid17021 (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Walker, Alice, 1967-2007, undated; cuid17022 (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Walker, Alice: Drafts of "Alice at Spelman"by Howard Zinn, undated; cuid17023 (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - War, 1946, 1950, 1962-1999, undated; cuid17024 (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - War, 2000-2002; cuid17025 (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - War, 2003-2006; cuid17026 (Box 66, Folder 31)
  - War, 2007-2009, undated; cuid17027 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - War, undated; cuid17028 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - War: Bombing (includes lengthy letter on Pearl Harbor from Japanese-American), 2000-2008, undated; cuid17029 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - War: Business and War (including oil), 1997-2002; cuid17030 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - War: Business and War (including oil), 2003-2004, undated; cuid17031 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - War: "Just War" - Annotated Draft (I), undated; cuid17032 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - War: "Just War" - Annotated Draft (II), undated; cuid17033 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - War: Notes on War, undated; cuid17034 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - War: War and Free Speech, 1963, 1968, 1973, 1974, undated; cuid17035 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - War: War Resistance, 1966-1990, undated; cuid17036 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Weapons of Mass Destruction, 2002-2004, undated; cuid17037 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Weapons of Mass Destruction: "Our WMD", 2002-2005, undated; cuid17038 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - We Now Know: Rethinking Cold War History by J.L. Gaddis: Reviews, 1999, undated; cuid17039 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - "Where Are They Now?" (former students and others): Correspondence, 1980-1985; cuid17040 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - "Where Are They Now?" (former students and others): Correspondence, 1986-1993, undated; cuid17041 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - "Where Are They Now?" (former students and others): News Clippings, Articles and Related Materials, 1981-1993; cuid17042 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - "Where Are They Now?" (former students and others): News Clippings, Articles and Related Materials, 1982-1986, 1990, undated; cuid17043 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - "Where Are They Now?" (former students and others): News Clippings, Articles and Related Materials, undated; cuid17044 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - "A Whistleblower's Guide to the Federal Bureaucracy" by Mark Ryter, Government Accountability Project, 1977; cuid17045 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Women's History: to 1900 (research material - notes, articles), 1976-1986, undated; cuid17046 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Women's History: 1900 to Now (research materials - notes, articles), 1975-1981, undated; cuid17047 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Women's History: Annotated Pages from A People's History..., [1979]; cuid17048 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Women's Rights, 1979-1984, undated; cuid17049 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - World War II, 1967-1995, undated; cuid17050 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - World War II, undated; cuid17051 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - World War II: Hiroshima, 1958-1981; cuid17052 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - World War II: Hiroshima, 1995, 2001, 2005, undated; cuid17053 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - World War II: Japanese Relocation, 1955, 1976-1988, undated; cuid17054 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - World War II: Nazis (Post War), 1982-1988, undated; cuid17055 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Yeshiva University: National Labor Relations Board v. Yeshiva University, 1980; cuid17056 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Zhivago (notes), undated; cuid17057 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Zinn Notes: "for Talk", 2004, 2009; cuid17058 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Zinn Notes: "for Talk", 2009, undated; cuid17059 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Zinn Notes and Fragments: Various (I), undated; cuid17060 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Zinn Notes and Fragments: Various (II), undated; cuid17061 (Box 68, Folder 13)
- Series IX: Books, with Zinn Annotations, 1929-1997
  A number of books from Howard Zinn's personal library were acquired with his papers. Many of them have been transferred to the Tamiment Library. The books in this series were retained with the papers because of the many annotations they contain.
  - American Holocaust: Columbus, Christianity and the Conquest of the Americas by David E. Stannard (advance proof), 1992; cuid17062 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - America's Working Women compiled and edited by Rosalyn Baxandall, Linda Gordon and Susan Reverby, 1976; cuid17063 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Anarchy, State, and Utopia by Robert Nozick, 1968; cuid17064 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Beirut Diary by Sis Levin, 1989; cuid17065 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Central America, Anatomy of a Conflict by Robert S. Leiken, 1984; cuid17066 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Dickens, his Character, Comedy, and Career by Hasketh Pearson, 1949; cuid17067 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - El Salvador: Central America in the New Cold War edited by Marvin E. Gettleman and Others, 1982; cuid17068 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Escape from Evil by Ernest Becker, 1975; cuid17069 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - The Federalist or the New Constitution by Hamilton, Jay and Madison, 1929; cuid17070 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - God and the State by Michael Bakunin, 1970; cuid17071 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - The Great Conspiracy Trial by Jason Epstein, 1970; cuid17072 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Helen Keller Her Socialist Years by Philip S. Foner, 1967; cuid17073 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - A History of the American People by Paul Johnson (includes book review by Zinn), 1997; cuid17074 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - History of the Commune of 1871 by Lissagaray (translation by Eleanor Marx Aveling), 1967; cuid17075 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - In a Time of Torment by I.F. Stone, 1967; cuid17076 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Jailed for Freedom, The Story of the Militant American Suffragist Movement by Doris Stevens, 1976; cuid17077 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Jean Paul Marat, A Study in Radicalism by Louis R. Gottschalk, 1967; cuid17078 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Justice: Alternative Political Perspectives by James Sterba, 1980; cuid17079 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Keeper of Concentration Camps, Dillon S. Myer and American Racism by Richard Drinnon, 1987; cuid17080 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Kissinger by Martin Kalb and Bernard Kalb, 1974; cuid17081 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Land by Daniel M. Friedenberg, 1992; cuid17082 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - The Life and Selected Writings of Thomas Jefferson (editors Koch and Peden), 1944; cuid17083 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Marx: Capital by Karl Marx (1906 Copyright), undated; cuid17084 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Marx: The Civil War in the United States by Karl Marx and Frederick Engels, 1937; cuid17085 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Marx: The Cologne Communist Trial by Karl Marx and Frederick Engels, 1971; cuid17086 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Marx: Karl Marx His Life and Thought by David McLellan, 1977; cuid17087 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Marx: Karl Marx The Story of His Life by Franz Mehring, 1962; cuid17088 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Marx: The Letters of Karl Marx selected and translated by Saul K. Padover, 1979; cuid17089 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Marx: The Marx-Engels Reader edited by Robert C. Tucker, 1978; cuid17090 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Marx: Writings on the Paris Commune by Karl Marx and Frederick Engels (edited by Hal Draper), 1971; cuid17091 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Memoirs of a Revolutionist by Peter Kropotkin, 1962; cuid17092 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - The Oppenheimer Case by Philip M. Stern, 1969; cuid17093 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - The Politics of Authenticity by Marshall Berman, 1970; cuid17094 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - The Rosenberg File by Ronald Radosh and Joyce Milton, 1983; cuid17095 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Search for a Method by Jean-Paul Sartre, 1963; cuid17096 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Selected Writings on Anarchism by P.A. Kropotkin, 1970; cuid17097 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - The Soul of Man Under Socialism by Oscar Wilde, 1969; cuid17098 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - The Tales of Hoffman edited by Levine, McNamee and Greenberg, 1970; cuid17099 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - A Thousand Days, John F. Kennedy in the White House by Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr., 1965; cuid17100 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Turning the Tide by Noam Chomsky, 1985; cuid17101 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Under the Eagle, US Intervention in Central America and the Caribbean by Jenny Pearce, 1981; cuid17102 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - The Wise Minority by Leon Friedman, 1971; cuid17103 (Box 73, Folder 2)
- Series X: Audio-Visual Material, 1957-2009
  This large series spans 11 linear feet, housing 466 individual items – VHS tapes, DVDs, audio recordings (reel-to-reel, cassette and CD), as well as a few older formats which cover more than fifty years of Howard Zinn's teaching, activism and public appearances. Class lectures and discussions are common as well as appearances by Zinn on radio programs as an interviewee, guest speaker or lecturer. The VHS tapes and DVDs also include performances of Zinn's plays and readings as well as a rough cut of You Can't be Neutral on a Moving Train.
  In addition to Zinn, other notable individuals such as Alice Walker, Noam Chomsky, Arundhati Roy, Eqbal Ahmad and Studs Terkel also appear.
  - Subseries X:A: Audio Cassettes, 1968-2009
    - Howard Zinn and Daniel Berrigan: Lecture on Hanoi Trip, Vietnam Committee for the Defense of Human Rights (Boston University, MA), 1968; cuid17104 (Box 86, Cd 1, Box 74, Cassette 1)
      In a small portion of this recording, a POW speaks about his cell mate, John McCain.
    - Howard Zinn: Unidentified Class Discussion, [1970]; cuid17105 (Box 74, Cassette 2)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 55 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge; poor audio quality.
    - Howard Zinn and William F. Buckley: Reform or Revolution (Tufts University, Medford, MA) Part 1, Jan 11, 1971; cuid17106 (Box 74, Cassette 3)
      Duration: 61 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn and William F. Buckley: Reform or Revolution (Tufts University, Medford, MA) Part 2, Jan 11, 1971; cuid17107 (Box 74, Cassette 4)
    - Howard Zinn and William F. Buckley: Reform or Revolution (Tufts University, Medford, MA) Part 3 / Howard Zinn: Speech (Boston Common, MA), Jan 11, 1971 / May 5, 1971; cuid17108 (Box 74, Cassette 5)
      Duration: 38 Minutes.
    - Children's Music / Unidentified Class Discussion [University of Paris, Vincennes], May 16, 1974 / undated; cuid17109 (Box 88, Cassette 6)
      Duration: 119 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge.
    - Herbert Marcuse: Interviewed by Bill Moyers / John Dos Passos, The Body of an American, 1974; cuid17110 (Box 74, Cassette 7)
      Duration: 55 Minutes.
    - Music and Sound Effects Emma (New York, NY), 1975; cuid17111 (Box 74, Cassette 8)
      Duration: 35 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge
    - Music / Howard Zinn: Class Discussion on Women, Oct 28, 1976; cuid17112 (Box 74, Cassette 9)
      Duration: 50 Minutes, Preservation Note: Poor audio quality.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Discussion, Regulating the Poor, Challenging Information, Fall 1976; cuid17113 (Box 74, Cassette 10)
      Duration: 52 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge; re-spliced to leader; Poor audio quality.
    - Howard Zinn: Discussion of the Film Salt of the Earth in "Law and Justice" Class / John Prine, "Your Flag Decal Won't Get You into Heaven Anymore", 1976, undated; cuid17114 (Box 74, Cassette 11)
      Duration: 64 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge; Poor audio quality.
    - Howard Zinn: the FBI and the RCMP (Radio Canada/CBC Presént Nationale, French Language), Jan 12, 1977; cuid17115 (Box 74, Cassette 12)
      Duration: 25 Minutes, Preservation Note: Poor audio quality; Side 2 is BLANK.
    - Howard Zinn and [Jon] Westling: Discussion on Equity, Mar 10, 1980; cuid17116 (Box 74, Cassette 13)
      Duration: 79 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge; Low volume.
    - Howard Zinn: Visions of a New Society (Pendle Hill, PA) Part 1, May 6, 1980; cuid17117 (Box 86, Cd 1-2, Box 74, Cassette 14)
    - Howard Zinn: Visions of a New Society (Pendle Hill, PA) Part 2, May 6, 1980; cuid17118 (Box 86, Cd 1, Box 74, Cassette 15)
    - Howard Zinn: Grievance Meeting with Provost (Includes Joseph Meng, Eugene Green and Mary Mitchell), Nov 12, 1980; cuid17119 (Box 74, Cassette 16)
      Duration: 74 Minutes, Preservation Note: Low volume.
    - Howard Zinn: Interview, Great Atlantic Radio Conspiracy, 1980; cuid17120 (Box 74, Cassette 17)
      Duration: 63 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Untitled Lecture (Scottsdale Community College, Phoenix, AZ), [1980]; cuid17121 (Box 74, Cassette 18)
      Duration: 32 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is BLANK.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Plato - Apology and Crito, Feb 2, 1981; cuid17122 (Box 74, Cassette 19)
      Duration: 92 Minutes, Preservation Note: Tape re-housed in new cartridge; tape was repaired.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Colonialism and the Distribution of Money, 1981; cuid17123 (Box 74, Cassette 20)
      Duration: 16 min., Preservation Note: Due to deterioration of the source tape, only 9 minutes of side 1 and 6 minutes of side 2 were digitized.
    - Howard Zinn: Resistance to the Vietnam War (Central Michigan University, Mount Pleasant, MI) Part 1, Apr 28, 1982; cuid17124 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Cassette 21)
    - Howard Zinn: Resistance to the Vietnam War (Central Michigan University, Mount Pleasant, MI) Part 2, Apr 28, 1982; cuid17125 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Cassette 22)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Race and Malcolm X, Oct 14, 1982; cuid17126 (Box 74, Cassette 23, Box 86)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Freedom of Speech Part 1, Oct 26, 1982; cuid17127 (Box 74, Cassette 24)
      Preservation Note: Sticky shed. Held for incubation.; Not transferred - incubation unsuccessful
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Freedom of Speech Part 2, Oct 29, 1982; cuid17128 (Box 74, Cassette 25)
      Duration: 60 Minutes, Preservation Note: Re-housed in new cartridge shell.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Freedom of Information Part 1, [Nov] 1982; cuid17129 (Box 74, Cassette 26)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Freedom of Information, Part 2, Nov 23, 1982; cuid17130 (Box 74, Cassette 27)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Labor and the Law Parts 1 and 2, Nov 1982, Dec 2, 1982; cuid17131 (Box 74, Cassette 28)
      Duration: 83 Minutes, Preservation Note: Re-housed in new cartridge shell. Side 2: large gaps in content removed for access file.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Race and Malcolm X, 1982; cuid17132; 1 CD (Box 74, Cassette 29, Box 86, Cd 1)
    - Howard Zinn: Is There an Ethics in Foreign Policy? (Assumption College, Worchester, MA) Part 1, Mar 16, 1983; cuid17133 (Box 74, Cassette 30)
      Duration: 92 Minutes, Preservation Note: During Q & A, questions are hard to decipher.
    - Howard Zinn: Is There an Ethics in Foreign Policy? (Assumption College, Worchester, MA) Part 2, Mar 16, 1983; cuid17134 (Box 74, Cassette 31)
      Duration: 36 Minutes, Preservation Note: During Q & A, questions are hard to decipher.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on the Constitution, Law and Justice, Sep 15, 1983; cuid17135 (Box 74, Cassette 32)
      Duration: 83 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Civil Disobedience, Sep 20, 1983; cuid17136 (Box 74, Cassette 33)
      Duration: 96 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on the Black Struggle (with announcements at beginning of class), Oct 4, 1983; cuid17137 (Box 74, Cassette 34)
      Duration: 74 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture (Law and Justice), Oct 6, 1983; cuid17138 (Box 74, Cassette 35)
      Duration: 54 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Racial Inequality, Oct 11, 1983; cuid17139; 1 CD (Box 74, Cassette 36, Box 86, Cd 1)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Malcolm X, Oct 13, 1983; cuid17140; 1 CD (Box 86, Cd 1, Box 74, Cassette 37)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Free Speech, Oct 25, 1983; cuid17141 (Box 74, Cassette 38)
      Duration: 65 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on War and Free Speech, Nov 1, 1983; cuid17142 (Box 74, Cassette 39)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on the U.S. Invasion of Grenada, Nov 3, 1983; cuid17143 (Box 74, Cassette 40)
      Duration: 60 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Vietnam, Nov 15, 1983; cuid17144 (Box 74, Cassette 41)
      Duration: 72 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture with [Steve Carpenter] - FBI and Thought Police, Nov 22, 1983; cuid17145 (Box 74, Cassette 42)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on Daniel Ellsberg and the Vietnam War, Nov 1983; cuid17146 (Box 74, Cassette 43)
      Duration: 95 Minutes.
    - Howard Zinn: Emma Goldman and Anarchism, Dec 8, 1983; cuid17147 (Box 74, Cassette 44)
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on the Rosenberg Case, [Fall 1983]; cuid17148 (Box 74, Cassette 45)
      Duration: 68 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: Class Lecture on U.S. Involvement with Chile, Fall 1983; cuid17149 (Box 74, Cassette 46)
      Duration: 94 Minutes
    - WHDH Mike Mill Show: Howard Zinn on U.S. Involvement in Central America and MA Referendum to End Funding for US Military Involvement in El Salvador, Honduras and Nicaragua, Oct 1984; cuid17150 (Box 74, Cassette 47)
      Duration: 121 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: Teach-In on American Intervention, Madison, WI, Apr 12, 1985; cuid17151 (Box 74, Cassette 48)
      Duration: 54 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 1: At beginning the recorder is turned on and off several times. This is raw content heard in edited form on TAM543_cuid17152.
    - WORT Backporch Radio Broadcasting: A Public Affair - Howard Zinn, Teach-In on American Intervention (Madison, WI), Apr 12, 1985; cuid17152 (Box 74, Cassette 49)
      Duration: 64 Minutes, Preservation Note: This has the same content - in edited and much cleaner form - as TAM542_cuid17151.
    - Black Rose Lecture Series: Howard Zinn - "Marx and Bakunin: A Dialogue", Nov 15, 1985; cuid17153 (Box 74, Cassette 50)
      Duration: 85 Minutes, Preservation Note: Audio volume low
    - Ron Kovic Speaking to Howard Zinn's Class on Law and Justice, Oct 30, 1986; cuid17154 (Box 74, Cassette 51)
      Duration: 69 Minutes
    - Howard Zinn: "Second Thoughts on the First Amendment," (includes Q and A, Community Church of Boston, MA), Nov 16, 1986; cuid17155 (Box 74, Cassette 52)
    - WSLU: Evening Report - Howard Zinn, Interview on the Vietnam War, (Canton, NY), Mar 12, 1987; cuid17156 (Box 74, Cassette 53)
      Duration: 26 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
    - Howard Zinn: "Other American Dreams: Resistance in U.S. History," (Hampshire College, Amherst, MA), Sep 15, 1987; cuid17157 (Box 74, Cassette 54)
      Duration: 85 Minutes
    - Sender Garlin: Lecture on the Life and Death of Joe Hill (University of Colorado, Boulder, CO), Jan 25, 1988; cuid17158 (Box 74, Cassette 55)
    - Howard Zinn: Last Class at Boston University (Boston, MA), Apr 1988; cuid17159 (Box 86, Cd 1, Box 74, Cassette 56)
    - WORT Backporch Radio Broadcasting: Second Opinion - Howard Zinn Interviewed by Erwin Knoll, Dec 1, 1988; cuid17160 (Box 87, Cassette 57)
      Duration: 30 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
    - Sender Garlin: Lecture on Mark Twain - Social Critic (University of Colorado, Boulder, CO), 1988; cuid17161 (Box 87, Cassette 58)
      Duration: 73 Minutes
    - KGNU: Howard Zinn, Second Thoughts on the First Amendment (lecture, Boulder, CO) Tape 1, 1989; cuid17162 (Box 87, Cassette 59)
    - KGNU: Howard Zinn, Second Thoughts on the First Amendment (lecture, Boulder, CO) Tape 2, 1989; cuid17163 (Box 87, Cassette 60)
      Duration: 74 Minutes
      Scope and Contents
      Side 2 is an interview with Zinn
    - Lehigh-Pocono Committee of Concern (LEPOCO) 25th Anniversary Dinner: Howard Zinn - Surprises in History (Bethlehem, PA), Mar 9, 1990; cuid17164 (Box 87, Cassette 61)
      Duration: 76 Minutes
    - Emma: A Play in Two Acts about Emma Goldman, American Anarchist (No 1) by Howard Zinn, Performed in Tokyo (Japanese Version), May 24, 1990; cuid17165 (Box 87, Cassette 62)
    - Emma: A Play in Two Acts about Emma Goldman, American Anarchist (No 2) by Howard Zinn, Performed in Tokyo (Japanese Version), May 24, 1990; cuid17166 (Box 87, Cassette 63)
      Duration: 57 Minutes
    - KPFK: Continent to Continent - Howard Zinn, "Columbus: Villain Portrayed as Hero," Also Includes Odessa Ramirez and Phillip Tajitsu Nash (Los Angeles, CA), Oct 3, 1990; cuid17167 (Box 87, Cassette 64)
      Duration: 95 Minutes, Preservation Note: re-housed in a new cartridge.
    - WMFO: Howard Zinn - Just and Unjust Wars, Mar 8, 1991; cuid17168 (Box 87, Cassette 65)
      Duration: 45 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 1: @ 00:33:00;xx - beginning of occasional glitchy speed issues. Side 2 is blank
    - WOMR: Two Good Arms - Howard Zinn on the Julius and Ethel Rosenberg Trial, Jun 1991; cuid17169 (Box 87, Cassette 66)
      Duration: 45 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
    - WOMR: Two Good Arms - Howard Zinn on the Julius and Ethel Rosenberg Trial/ Sacco and Vanzetti Commemoration (Aug 23, 1990)/ May Day (1991) Presentation/ Report on Jesse Helm's Attack on the National Endowment for the Arts (Provincetown, MA), Jun 1991/ Aug 23, 1990/ 1991/ undated; cuid17170 (Box 87, Cassette 67)
      Duration: 66 Minutes
    - Monadnock Summer Lyceum: Howard Zinn - "A Second Look at the First Amendment: Free Speech" (Petersborough Unitarian Church, Peterborough, NH), Jul 7, 1991; cuid17171 (Box 87, Cassette 68)
    - New Hampshire Public Radio: Howard Zinn - Interview Tape 1, Jul 11, 1991; cuid17172 (Box 87, Cassette 69)
      Duration: 7 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
    - New Hampshire Public Radio: Howard Zinn - Interview Tape 2, Jul 11, 1991; cuid17173 (Box 87, Cassette 70)
      Preservation Note: Duplicate of cuid17172 - NOT TRANSFERRED
    - Howard Zinn: "Columbus Legacy: 1492-1992" (Wellfleet Public Library, Wellfleet, MA), Aug 29, 1991; cuid17174 (Box 87, Cassette 71)
    - Howard Zinn: "Just and Unjust Wars" (Wellfleet Public Library, Wellfleet, MA), Sep 3, 1991; cuid17175 (Box 87, Cassette 72)
      Duration: 72 Minutes, Preservation Note: Audio in right channel only
    - WOMR: Howard Zinn - "Second Thoughts on the First Amendment" (Recorded Sep 7, 1991, Broadcast Dec 13, 1991 and Dec 20, 1991, Wellfleet, MA), cuid17176 (Box 87, Cassette 73)
      Duration: 58 Minutes
    - Gray Panthers Meeting: Howard Zinn, Economic Bill of Rights (Cambridge, MA), Oct 18, 1991; cuid17177 (Box 87, Cassette 74)
      Duration: 86 Minutes
    - Radio Free Maine: Howard Zinn - Speaking Out on the CIA (Franklin Pierce College, NH), Oct 28, 1991; cuid17178 (Box 87, Cassette 75)
    - WBAI: Howard Zinn - Multiculturalism in Education, Nov 30, 1991; cuid17179 (Box 87, Cassette 76)
      Duration: 50 Minutes
      Contains multiple programs recorded off the radio.
    - Radio Free Maine / Massachusetts Civil Liberties Union: "Born in the USA- 200 Years Old Today, Bill of Rights Celebration" (Includes Barry Crimmins, Ira Glasser, Molly Ivins, Mel King, Howard Zinn and Ted O'Brien, Old South Meeting House, Boston, MA) Part 1, Dec 15, 1991; cuid17180 (Box 87, Cassette 77)
      Duration: 88 Minutes
    - Radio Free Maine / Massachusetts Civil Liberties Union: "Born in the USA- 200 Years Old Today, Bill of Rights Celebration" (Includes Barry Crimmins, Ira Glasser, Molly Ivins, Mel King, Howard Zinn and Ted O'Brien, Old South Meeting House, Boston, MA) Part 2, Dec 15, 1991; cuid17181 (Box 87, Cassette 78)
    - WOMR: Talking Together, Holiday Greetings, Dec 27, 1991; cuid17182 (Box 87, Cassette 79)
      Duration: 44 Minutes, Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank
    - Radio Free Maine: Howard Zinn - Aftermath of Persian Gulf War; Just and Unjust Wars (Boston College, MA), Feb 5, 1992; cuid17183 (Box 87, Cassette 80)
      Duration: 95 Minutes